[Music]
you're listening to the AI native Dev
brought to you by
[Music]
[Applause]
Tesla hello everyone and welcome to the
podcast again on this episode this is a
very quick follow up after our previous
chat Felipe we talked a lot about how
Filipe created applications and services
Etc with using Claude 35 and in
particular the projects functionality
that that effectively allowed you to to
create prompts to create specifications
and so forth for those of you who
haven't watched haven't listened to that
first episode first of all feel free to
do that or you're more than welcome to
to carry on watching but for Lee you're
a data scientist you're a programmer
you're a PhD you're well do kind of like
your education learning teachings yeah
really interested in AI generation of
code and the future of that AI uh has to
play in software development and today
you're going to be showing us showing us
a screen share of of your interactions
with Claude 31 just for the listeners
this is an episode which is only on
YouTube obviously because we're going to
be doing a ton of screen sharing so you
won't find us on the podcast but the
first episode of the chat is on both of
those I'm going to add the the screen
share to the page now fipe talk us
through first of all when you after you
decided to use cl35 after you decided to
use the projects and this is what you
were faced with talk us through the
various aspects of the UI on the page
and how you went about creating in this
case Cards Against AI which is an
application that you wrote effectively
as a test drive for cl projects yeah
just for those who didn't listen to the
first podcast like that quick
introduction on purpose of this this is
a control experiment that I did and I
really wanted to test the raw power of
clot 3.5 I could have done this with a
vs code extension cursor of any of those
different tools but I really wanted to
test the raw power of clot I really felt
that the future is product spec Centric
versus code spec code Centric and I was
really forcing myself to to apply it
that and I decided to do cars against AI
because it's something that I started
from scratch that I didn't have much
Clarity over what I wanted and I wanted
also to see how Claud can help me write
the specifications of these products and
that's the key piece right because a lot
of people go to uh a GPT and think
straight away about the code give me
some code that does this yeah whereas
you went with the route of give me a
specification from these prompts and and
from our discussion with which I can
then go ahead and create an application
so it was a slightly longer term path
really because once you have the
specification it's it's there it's more
concrete and that's your source of Truth
when you ask for code from a GPT what's
your source of Truth you can't just keep
you can't keep your prompts unless it's
one prompt and then that one prompt is
presumably more like a specification
anyways so talk us through this page
sure so I have a project that is called
cars against AI there is some
instructions that you can add so in this
case I just put this instruction your
CTO of a creative agency blah blah blah
when brain stering ideas about design be
brief technology agnostic ask as many
clarifying questions as possible before
making up your mind is very important
turns it more into into a chat chat
conversation and it really helps with
the blank page problem and what we were
discussing in the previous podcast about
that we can be lazy and expect that one
single sentence can produce what we want
this protects us from that because one
single sentence is not clear enough so
CL will ask you questions this one is
also quite nice mer diagrams text snacku
details it's nice when you instruct CLA
how do you want cl to interact and what
do you want cl to provide to you and Mer
diagrams are quite useful because they
can be rendered on the artifacts we will
see that then I just outlined the
preferred text stack and some design
principles but I think that's a personal
taste doesn't matter that much and this
is like your system prompt that's exact
these instructions are common to every
chat every chat in this entire so now I
have all the chats that I used to create
this app so as as you can imagine as you
can see like there's a lot of them I did
a lot of different Chats on that and you
have this interface where you can add
content so I just add content and I can
add any text file that I want so so
that's not just text files that Claude
creates here although if you do create a
file you can push it into there but you
could pull in whatever files you want
okay but I also can the artifacts that
it creates I can just ask it to
integrate them into the project
structure but just to give you a better
view over that this is what we're
talking about like this
folder this folder has all of the
specifications that I want so how did
you pull it out of CLA then to to get
that vs code let's take a look into that
okay so let's see for example the open
API specifications to answer that
question so here I say okay the
definition of roles we were talking
about roles in the prev podcast you're a
senior backend developer with extensive
experience in AP design please review
backend specifications front end
specifications and set up DV that's all
you need to design the API which is the
glue point and propose open API
specification so ask clarifying
questions and it ask a lot of questions
I answer back all of those questions and
then I get these okay so this is the
power of artifacts that I can actually
review here and if I modify it then this
same file will be modified and then I
just copy paste this into open API and
that's it so couple of questions there
then so so the role the role is first of
all it's not necessarily a structure
within Claude projects it's it's
literally the opening line that you put
in and that sets the context for the
conversation and so on every every
request it presumably uses I think it
uses everything in that chat as context
so it automatically continues with that
role the specification did you ask for
is that like a yaml specification right
yes did you ask specifically for a yaml
specification or is that yeah I I I
asked for open API specification
standard yeah a standard that any
framework can can talk to also something
we talked about Auditors so look at this
please contr the specification we set up
that SQL script and make sure they are
compatible and using the same names if
not please modify so these type of
things are are quite useful and was was
this the same this is a different role
though right no this is the same role
but you're turning it into more of an
auditor role now and then it realizes
makes a mistakes he modifies some things
I don't know what it modified but it
modifi some stuff and that's it curious
you don't know what it modified so no I
do know I'm not right now but oh I see
yeah yeah but eventually I do know so my
question there was going to be how much
you look into like from
point of view verus a more
automated
path how much are you looking at every
single thing it creates versus putting
it throwing it all together and seeing
what happens at the end in this case we
all use git as s for developers and I
think it's instrumental to use git yeah
for this so what I would do is I will
just add this file to vs code once I add
it I will stage the file I don't have to
commit it yep I just stage the file and
then I copy paste the modifications and
that and I can see the diff and then I
that's how I survey how things are being
modified gotcha but yeah I have to
review and audit everything except for
the front and part work I mean I do
review it but just because I'm curious
and sometimes probably it will probably
it's good to it's definitely good to do
that validation and verification
afterwards anyway but sometimes I'm
guessing Claude will probably tell you
the changes it made as well but yeah
it's not you
just rely on its description it's good
to validate so I think makes sense what
you're doing yeah yeah I don't think
we're there yet I think we we still have
to survey that yeah let's go into the
fail back in path you you asked me that
question during yeah this is so this is
this is a so what makes a failed path
first of all what makes a fail path as I
said in the previous podcast I'm the one
who made the mistake it was the first
implementation of the pend and I
realized that I didn't do things in the
right order yeah because I saw that the
API is the glue point between the front
end the back end so I thought I have to
start by the API it's not true I had to
start by the AP open API definition
that's what I had to start with the open
API definition not the implementation
and then once you have the definition
then you start by data model the
services layer and then you have data
model Services layer you have enough
context to actually create the API
straight yep so that's what I realized
and actually I realized yes and no I as
I I I just felt that I took a path where
I asked straight away implement the API
and it was getting messy he needed to do
a lot of modifications I do know about
backend developer development so I knew
this is this is not the right path so I
simply say provide a summary of what we
did suggest an approach for future
implementations mermaid diagram and they
gave you this diagram which I didn't
like that much so I I asked it like just
make it simple and at the end this is
what this is the conclusion so with a
discussion that I had with the these R
saying things are not working out please
summarize what we did wrong what didn't
work and at the end this is what it
suggested start with the da detail
specification review data model design
service layer implementation API schema
definition and API input implementation
so my error was going straight to this
without doing these two first yeah so
there's a lot of hallucinations going on
of how yeah cuz it always wants to give
an answer right whether it's right or so
at the end that's what I did for the
next backend implementation and it
worked perfectly I focused first on the
service layer API schema definition and
B done so what does it look like then in
your kind of like G flow when you hit a
dead end what does it look like in terms
of the the G flow but also then how do
you take your learnings into the next
that's a good question so I just did a
branch for the back end okay and then I
just
put a tag that it was a dead end yeah
and then I just continue with my other
Branch that's it yeah as simple as that
that looks familiar and from a g point
of you yeah it's not not nothing fancy
very simple just a branch that didn't go
further that's it and what I did with
that what I did was learn basically like
that that's all it was a learning path
and now I know a better way of doing it
I just threw away all of the code all of
the code that I did with that was thrown
away I didn't look back and I simply
used that as a learning path and the
thing is that it's so cheap that it
doesn't matter like it's like at the
first back end failed path I was like a
damn it it's painful but then I thought
I've only been doing this for 30 minutes
1 hour who cares let's just throw it
away and start again and that's the
beauty when you realize that when you go
past that fear of starting over that we
have as developers because it's a lot of
work just doesn't matter what did I
learn this path and this let just try
another one and I think that's curious
It's The Learning piece right what have
you learned from it and how can you take
that back into the next one to make it
easier or FAS and I think you do ask for
a Handover right yeah exactly yeah the
Handover which I then include
here the suggest an implementation path
and key learnings areas of improvement
and so on and so forth I don't think
it's worth it to go through the details
but uh yeah suggested approach for
implementation
yeah yeah so that's that was the setup I
had for cars against Ai and I think it
it gives a good overv review I think
moving forward you can achieve something
similar uh with
cursor I think I will still use CLA for
react mockups and for product natural
language product specifications I think
it's quite good for that so show us the
the react mockup because I think that's
that's super interesting we did a blog
when our designer actually Rachel did a
Blog about how she did some of this with
some front- end design stuff that she
was looking she actually updated her
website after afterwards yeah let's see
what it looks like here okay your senior
front end developer blah blah blah you
have a key knif for detail blah blah
blah and then important thing go to
front end specification and the open API
jamble file this will give you an
overall idea of what I want help me
design the front ends give me some react
visuals first this is
important because yeah if you don't say
that it will implement the whole thing
and I don't want it to implement the
whole thing I first want to nail down
the design and once I have the design
proper the proper design just breaking
it into breaking it down effectively and
then almost giving your approvals for
for the various bits which are then
later in yeah so this is the homepage
this is the game page I didn't like
let's spare the details no need to go
into that but then I had some I know I
some things that I had to change please
do this do that and it started to change
complete game page and as you can see
like you have an evolution here of the
whole
app add a thir thing column add the
score and submit bottom to the top blah
I just tell it what I want and then
let's go to the part where we actually
implemented which I think it's quite
nice so at the end this is what we get
and then if it's functional this is
actually quite powerful it's functional
you know how much yeah how how much did
you have to actually change under the
covers to get it to
work not that much look at this I don't
know one two three four five six six
prompts were there any issues with the
code rather
I don't know and I don't care because at
this point I only look at the visuals
it's just the it's just the not the back
end it's just the visuals just the front
end so in six prompts I got the visuals
for the homepage and and the complete
game page
yep and
then what I did is I did this prompt and
I think this prompt I also put it here
because I think it was quite important
it's also part of the specification
which is the the contract let's say
which is basically here I'm just saying
hey the front end will interact with the
back end following specifications found
on open API
final open please be careful to
understand how to integrate it and what
data to expect from each API call yeah
and then I said the homepage component
is going to interact in this way and the
game page in this way so I'm just saying
which end points are you going to call
in which different situations yeah and
then once I do that
it goes for the implementation and yeah
I think I said ask is this clear enough
do you think there are some missing
points this is really important to
always end your when in some key points
always ask for clarification ask me
clarifying questions it's quite useful
yeah and then you just do whatever we
will not implemented suggested endpoints
how do you suggest we proceed with
implementation and then you get the
whole code and then here a matter of
okay suggest a folder structure first C
the whole project and there you have it
and this looks like a real pain to have
to move all this across now to vade
right or or something yeah for sure but
that's why I always ask for
scaffolding like I always ask for
scaffold frontend yeah at least it
creates the folder structures on the
file names yeah yeah and the rest is
history that's a good I like that idea
that's a good idea yeah of course yeah
and then I got an error and then he just
modifies the error so it automatically
feeds that back in or you ask it to no I
I put the error in got you oh yeah I see
that yeah I put it in and then it
modifies stuff I run it I also got some
errors it's very apologetic isn't it I
apologize for that error how dare I
suggest C that doesn't work yeah when I
hit star game in the hom page the page
turns blank and does not bring me the
game page and then yeah and at the end
please show me the full cont that and
then yeah this one please me show me the
full content of the game page that's
actually not a nice thing that you have
in CLA which is it shows you what to
modify
sometimes it doesn't actually add
provide you with the full version give
me the full one yeah and then you you've
got this thing that doesn't work because
it's trying to it's trying to do a
rendering but I don't care about the
rendering I just want the code I just
copy paste the code anyway and then at
the end
you you got it I think that I came to
the end of of this part but yeah I think
this is the gist of it so if someone
wants to build an app from scratch
what's the how how they start sure
so I had this app we built at predicta
for chatting with your database okay so
I just use this as an example because I
already have a a readymade back end that
is work working yeah so let's try to do
the the front end of these uh I already
have a front end but let's try to do
another one just for the exercise yeah
so we should all chat with our databases
regular any yeah get to know them and
yeah I think it's important yeah it's
the human thing to do yeah because you
you shouldn't only talk to them when you
need something just generally how how
are you doing database yeah yeah so
you're senior frontend developer with
experience building react apps it's it's
quite similar to the old one it's not
very different D end this is just a
matter of taste so that's set now for
the whole everything that we every
discussion that we have in here and I I
actually started a project here where I
have my front end description I how I
want the outline to be I have my open
API schema definition so how much of
this did you create versus ask Claude to
create for you yeah so this one I I got
it from the back end okay yeah course
this is just the open API specification
from the back end and this is super
useful just so that when you do create
other pieces it connects nicely yeah
yeah because this is that's the last
place you want anything to hallucinate
or expect things to be there when
they're not it's that's the beauty of
Standards you know it's an open standard
everybody respects it and that's a
beauty this one I I wrote it on my own I
just wrote it I don't think it's I I
don't think I need yeah clot to write
this because it's quite simple okay and
then I just put all of those uh files
over here yeah okay yeah I already did
one but let's start one from scratch
okay so let's just copy paste The Prompt
just to save us some
time yeah please help me design the
front end according to front end. MD do
not Implement all of the code yet give
me some re mockups let's say mockups so
it knows what frontend MD is because
it's a file in the project knowledge so
let's see I
does okay this is a common error I I've
been getting this morning that I was not
getting before it's not an error really
this is proper code yeah which is you
are importing things things from
component UI button component and this
is does not allow us to render these
okay because we're not because it's not
something that we are supplying yeah
it's a best practice probably for people
who are developing code but they would
then import that into the environment so
let's say please include all
components in the same file and add
markup data because I saw that it said
that I need to implement an API whatever
I'll forget about that I just want to
see the visuals
yeah yeah so now it's mockup response
it's good gotcha
yeah the button just putting it all in
line yeah so with this be if you did
want to actually just import stuff this
would be quite annoying as well right
because if we did pull this out to vs
code we wouldn't want to necessarily in
line this all the time yeah so we would
presumably maybe want to make some
changes before we export just to say
okay let's assume we do these Imports
now and and so we can almost get it
right and then perform the Imports
afterwards perhaps yeah but this looks
much
nicer and I'm not seeing the rest let's
do a rest submit we're not seeing the
rest
so I am not seeing
the other cards only the input component
so as you can imagine I did learn a bit
about Rea all of this hacking I
apologize yeah very kind isn't
it looks a bit bigger
yeah back d o
that's interesting it it yeah it uses an
external Library yeah
yeah do not use react
done ah but there's always the fight
that you have here sometimes it's just
better to stop if you already know what
oh what is happening Claud did I break
CLA
keep
every thing in the same file now this is
an interesting tip here
because you you chose to edit that
versus writing a new so what's the value
of the edit versus adding a later prompt
yeah to to noise redu correct okay yeah
as simple as that noise reduction
because if it made a mistake but it
didn't make a mistake it just separating
into different into two different compon
files which makes it you cannot render
that here okay so because you cannot
render I cannot see it I cannot validate
it so that's why I'm asking it to keep
on the same file
so it's better to do it this way so that
you reduce the noise and you have a
cleaner context because otherwise you
will have a version with two separate
files and version with just everything
in one file so that's not ideal
yeah so he's still not interacting with
he's not giving us the full page
um I am still not seeing all
components and maybe because of the
non-determinism here as well it's
interesting because maybe had that
command had run or had that prompt run
four or five times a number of them
would have worked a number of them
wouldn't so it's like almost how how
down to your lock as well as to whether
it will do it or not because you don't
know which path it will take there you
have it this looks a bit better there
you have it now we have the the front
end maybe it's not as beautiful as I
would want to but it doesn't matter like
uh we could care about that we could
iterate and say for example I went
thought process and explanation to be in
the same row I want approve and
disapprove to be next to submit button
we could try all of the stuff but maybe
let's go to the more interesting part
which is okay now let's go and implement
this
okay so for that implementation this is
where I have the open API contract yes
okay so this frontend will interact with
back end following the specifications
found on file open api. yaml please read
carefully to understand blah blah blah
and then I simply say what happens we
only have two end points I think ask and
feedback yeah so ask that you submit a
query and then you get back like the
thought process the explanation the
results of the
query then approve or disapprove because
I want to have a feedback did I give
thumbs up thumbs down the right response
or not yeah exactly so now I just have
to tell it like please implement this
front end I'm going to cheat if you
don't mind to make it quicker just to
make it
quicker okay so this is the prompt so
frontend API contract what we just yeah
saw and you WR that or I wrote this yeah
for instructions on how to interact with
your backend proceed with implementation
and provide all necessary files and P
struct to execute this app provide a vas
script for scaffolding the skeleton of
the project provide full file context
and not just the editable parts
and provide yeah provide
instructions on how to set up and run m
front
and now this is in the same chat yeah as
the uh as the front end it has to be in
the same chat because it needs that as
context unless you pull that out to Sure
uh another file yeah and use that as
context yeah which I should actually I
think
that
these yeah I do think that this is what
is happening here okay okay this thing
is running and
it's let let it flow let
it but yeah that that's a mockup and
this mockup it's part of the product
specification in the way I used it it's
part of the product specification not so
where if we going back to the gitf flow
yeah where would you at What stages
typically based on your experience using
this as a as a workflow at what at what
places so far would you have coped that
the code across or even specifications
and and so forth across to to actually
perform a well stage it will commit at
various points yeah let's do that yeah
okay is now a good point then or would
you have done before now is a good point
now it's a good point to Stage not to
commit to Stage to Stage because now you
stage let's let's just do it
so maybe let's just do
one one for
that
sh
so yeah in this case this would be the
flow get in it
first okay get in
it and then I would just say um get
ad first I should have done it ad
specifications MH
yeah exactly and G
commit initial specifications this is
not the best comic but doesn't matter
and then get at scaffold and I will stop
there so why would you stop there not
because I'm not sure if this thing
working or not okay and if I say you
made this mistake blah blah blah
whatever change this and that that's the
cas you don't want to commit for every
single one of those so so I keep
iterating until okay now I I got to a
milestone where what CL provided me
works then I have a comment and for this
how do you add tests do you get CLA to
create them for you do you do is it more
visual based on your for a frontend I
have no idea how to test the front how
do I test for a front I have no idea
again like I'm a back end developer so
in that case I would just ask CL yeah
yeah generate some tests or click
through yourself but I guess with the
back end yeah I I I do I do the test
myself to the visual like the user test
of course I I do them but if you really
want to have hardcoded tests in that
case I would just ask cl to help me
write yeah and I guess from a back end
point of view as well you can get it to
gener start generating those or use some
other AI tools if you're if you do if
you're pulling that across into your IDE
codium or whatever it is to to do that
okay cool so yeah this is the workflow
now the next step will be to just
copypaste everything and run the
instructions as they said and see how
that goes yeah I do think that this is a
nice way of doing oh this is supposed to
be called
setup.sh
apparently
yeah yeah it doesn't matter I do think
that this is nice and everything as I
said at the beginning I wanted to test
the the row power of of cloth um I would
do it differently I would do it this way
MH let's forget about
this and then
composer
y so this is how we do it which is like
the equivalent you know mhm
actually
H that's not how I would do it precisely
but I would have to First Take This
code copy
it and
then
app
marup that
DSX I think what's the extension D
yeah
no and then and so this when it does
create it will automatically populate in
the in the curs obviously an ID as well
as as an a AI enabled assistant so as it
generates it automatically puts it in a
file structure right yeah
exactly but again I haven't tried cursor
as much as I would like to I I I've been
off for one month of this will be your
next step try that would be my next step
I don't know how good this will work I
would say this has to be quite powerful
but the idea is say doing the same but
here and then you hit
submit and what does this use under the
under the covers is this is there A5
this use CLA 35 as well
yeah and this presumably would also be
better in terms of if you are trying to
import things you can then start pulling
those components in versus requiring it
because you're not effectively running
it in a rapple whereby you need those
you can actually just run it using those
components so accept all yeah and then
as you can see like I have everything
here yeah and now it's okay if it
separates things into different files
it's that's the right way of doing it
yes so that will be for me the next step
I don't know if you want to give it a
try to see if this runs or maybe you can
see the other one let's try it let's try
let's try why not okay let's see so
let's follow the instructions here so
bash scaffold
okay
complete but like it hallucinated a bit
here like
at the end he did some stuff that are
quite weird just repeated it as
if this was actually not
necessary like this colding actually and
maybe I did a mistake here in that
because now we're talking
about because now we're talking about
cursor yeah that's my mistake as as we
were saying like sometimes when it
doesn't give you what you need maybe you
the one to mistake you confused it
because make sure you scaffold whole
project and add necessary configuration
file yeah so I don't need to say that
because we're in cursor at the moment
yeah cursor cursor already has the
instruction to scaffold everything yeah
so it's just duplicated that scaffold
yeah so let's leave this package
here no you know what let's do it
again let's do it
again doesn't
matter okay let's do it
again no that's not that one
but how to inter your backend Pro with
implementation and provide that's
obvious because we're in
cursor this we don't need
this Pro a full file content not just
the edit bars again this is not
necessary
yep y there's
two okay and
actually
imple
implement the front
end based on the
mockup found at
[Music]
follow front API
and open
API for instructions on how to
communicate with the back
end then we just don't need to put this
here and then simply Pro provide
instructions feels
faster I don't know why maybe maybe it's
the
UI yeah so accept all
so you say accept all and everything is
there yeah and let's just do mpm
install Okay CD analytics
frend something is missing there so it
didn't provide
a page Jon
yeah so
you
forgot that'ss good yeah
thinking
yeah
good what else should I do
so mpm install I should provide the
backend
API so let's create
a
end yeah and that's actually the address
it's just very
fine yeah it's there
okay
okay okay
source
and okay what else should we
do and then run Dev this this works
straight out
H I would have been
[Laughter]
amazed it's quite weird uh but wait is
there do we have a conflict okay and
then go to it's funny okay let me just
check because I think that I do have
a stuff running on Port just make sure
okay no this is not the case
but here this the
case like
down
okay yeah okay
so let's see
when I go to the URL I get
p and this is the problem then it's it's
giving it quite generic error responses
and also this is
where the fact that I'm not a front
developer and that I'm not proficient in
no GS yeah that's where I I start losing
because yeah it's good till it's not
when you're when it's generating stuff
but unless you actually know the details
and depth of it yeah we have a python
developer and a and a Java developer
trying to trying to debug JavaScript
right now which is exactly is not a good
space we need to check if there's an
issue with the main point let's let's
create our update analytics also make
sure you have an index okay it created
two new
files so this is where let's pause here
so this is
where I I should have done that but I
didn't
anyway Dropbox project
chat this is where I should have used
started using git yeah to actually see
what it's changing yeah oh I see to
compare better diff the the updates
there yeah and also it's like offering
things now that we didn't specifically
ask for so it's almost like we were
almost being too specific and it wasn't
generating enough for the app um get
ignore node modules
okay now this is something useful stage
All Stage all accept this
one okay and then let's go back to the
composer unless let's accept this
MH okay now I see that it actually
changed some stuff like the index that
HTML didn't have anything yeah and we
were missing the main. TX so this is a
great example of the import of using G
as your Budd
here so let's see if that changes the
output of
these there you have it amazing
yeah give me a list of
Brands there you have it there we go
amazing yeah yeah wow that was uh that
was super cool super it was awesome to
see that demo more end to end and I
think hopefully folks on on YouTube will
have will have seen some very
interesting things how to get started
and also showing how easy it is for two
backend developers ultimately to to Fon
and Java doing NOS there we go who' have
thought to BU a have a front end and and
connect to that back in so well using
the specs in particular as big pieces to
to connect different parts of the app
Felipe thank you so much for joining us
and thank you for sharing some live
coding using using cursor using Claude
CL products thank you Simon for having
me it's been wonderful two days
interacting with you and looking what
you were doing it's really great
conversations and everything I'm really
happy to be here amazing appreciate it
and tune in to the next episode thanks
all for listening
[Applause]
thanks for tuning in join us next time
on the AI native Dev brought to you by
Tesla
[Music]